# Kerem Kocaer

SENIOR CYBERSECURITY CONSULTANT

kk@foxtheory.uk +44 7889 641 570 London, Stockholm, Istanbul

Experienced security professional with a strong technical background, combined with a unique ability to understand the business and act as a bridge between senior management and technical teams. Able to lead and conduct security engagements of diverse complexities and deliver impactful reports.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2019/05 - Present

London, UK

WORKTOOLS | Co-founder, CTO

Building a Security, Compliance and Health monitoring platform, and enabling NCSC Cyber Essentials certification

for SMBs.

2018/09 - Present

London, UK

FOX THEORY | Freelance

Providing cybersecurity services, bug bounty assessments; developing IT solutions for the creative industries.

2015/06 - 2017/10

London, UK

JPMORGAN CHASE & CO. | Vice President

Co-leading the Global Red Team; Managing and conducting cybersecurity assessments, including adversary emulation, penetration testing, product evaluations.

2014/09 – 2015/06

London, UK

PWC UK | Manager

Managing the Threat & Vulnerability team, leading and conducting Red Team engagements, malware development, phishing campaigns, application and infrastructure penetration tests.

2011/08 - 2014/09 Stockholm, SE

PWC SWEDEN | Manager

Heading Technical Security Assessments team; Forensic investigations; IT Governance & Security; Security and awareness trainings for PwC and clients; Compliance audits of Windows AD against industry standards.

2008/04 - 2011/08 Stockholm, SE **BITSEC AB** | Consultant

Conducting Infrastructure and web application penetration testing; developing ISO 27001 ISMS and a national scheme based on Common Criteria for the security evaluation of IT systems.

### **EDUCATION**

2005 – 2007 KTH ROYAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Stockholm, SE MSc. Information & Communication Systems Security

2001 – 2005 GALATASARAY UNIVERSITY

Istanbul, TR BSc. Computer Engineering

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

Security CISSP Certified Information Systems Security Professional

**OSCP** Offensive Security Certified Professional

**GPEN** GIAC Penetration Tester \*

**GXPN** GIAC Exploit Researcher and Advanced Penetration Tester \*

GCFA GIAC Forensic Analyst \*

G2700 GIAC ISO 27000 Specialist \*

(\*) certifications not renewed

Languages English Fluent

French Fluent
Swedish Fluent
Turkish Fluent

## **KEY SKILLS**

Technical IT Security Red Team / Adversary Emulation / CBEST

Penetration Testing (Web / Infrastructure)

**Application Security** 

**Vulnerability Assessment** 

**IT Forensics** 

Information Security Standards, Frameworks and Best Practices, including ISO

27001, NCSC Cyber Essentials, Common Criteria, MS Threat

Modelling, etc.

Security Training Offensive Security, Application Security, Security Awareness,

SANS Mentor (2012-2017)

Programming Ruby, Rails, Python, Java, C, C#, VB.NET, PHP, SQL, HTML,

Javascript, React, CSS, UI Frameworks (Bootstrap, Semantic

UI, Bulma)